Do you think you'd be
okay speaking on camera?
So we can show you as Siti's friend?
But I want to protect my identity.
What if people say,
"That girl is the friend of a murderer"?
We were friends. We liked to hang out.
We liked talking, eating, shopping.
Hi.
Siti's really pretty and down to earth.
Somebody is having a baby...
She was always making jokes.
She's friendly and "happy go lucky."
Thank you. Buh-bye.
This is her last Facebook post.
The night before the murder,
Siti celebrated her
birthday at Hard Rock Cafe.
Siti!
Here we go!
One, two, three!
♪ Happy birthday to you... ♪
She seemed really happy.
♪ Happy birthday... ♪
We couldn't believe that she
murdered someone the next morning.
We are back with
an apparent assassination,
brazenly carried out
at an international airport.
Kim Jong-nam, the half-brother
of the North Korean leader Kim Jong-un,
was murdered in Malaysia...
...the sudden and mysterious
death of the half-brother
of the North Korean leader
Kim Jong-un.
Kim Jong-nam was at the
Kuala Lumpur International Airport
when he was reportedly poisoned.
...after he was sprayed
in the face with a chemical.
...by two female
assassins...
A cold-blooded execution,
straight from a spy movie,
local media reports say.
Two femme fatale killers
poisoning a mysterious political
figure with a chemical weapon.
Malaysian police said
the poison used
was the deadly VX nerve agent.
...one of the fastest-acting fatal
poisons that exists, according to scientists.
The U.S. and
South Korea believe the murder
was an assassination organized
by North Korean agents.
But North Korea
denies involvement in the crime.
Tonight, little is
known about the two women
who have just been arrested
in connection with the murder.
Were the women trained assassins
or innocent pawns of
North Korean agents?
I started covering the
Kim Jong-nam murder trial
from day one, when the first news broke.
A reporter's job is to
tell the world the truth.
But in Malaysia,
the freedom of press is limited.
Most of the big media agencies
are owned by the government.
So, it's hard to get the truth out.
But, I am lucky that my media
organization is not a local one.
So we are quite open
with what we can publish.
It's one of those big stories that is a
dream for a reporter to report on.
So around 9 AM, Kim Jong-nam walked
through this entrance to the terminal.
He was just alone. No one was with him.
And right behind this column,
there was one woman waiting for him.
This is Siti Aisyah,
the woman in a light gray shirt.
And from that way,
Doan Thi Huong was coming towards him.
She was wearing a white
T-shirt that says "LOL."
So he was supposed to print
out his boarding pass,
but before he was able to do that,
Kim Jong-nam was jumped
by Siti Aisyah and Doan.
And they allegedly smeared
VX chemical onto his face.
The women ran away.
And then from the CCTV footage you
can clearly see that Kim Jong-nam was
making this gesture to police officers
that these two women came up
to smear his face with a chemical.
And from there the police officers
escorted Kim Jong-nam towards the clinic.
You can see that he is starting to limp,
like he has already been
affected by something.
He was given medical attention,
but within an hour, he was dead.
Meanwhile, the two women,
they both went down to
level 2 to the toilet
to wash their hands.
It seems to suggest that
they knew that the chemical on their hands
is something dangerous.
They have a certain
cool, calculative
confidence in their walk.
Here is what I find interesting, because
she's walking and then she...
she looked into the CCTV camera.
As if challenging, you know?
Yeah, I just did that. So what?
Well, one thing is clear.
This is one of the most bizarre
murder plots in decades.
It really is incredible,
when you look at this woman,
who is acting in broad daylight.
Who are these women,
and do they work
for the North Korean regime?
Siti Aisyah and Doan Thi Huong
were charged with exposing
the deadly nerve agent VX
to Kim Jong-nam's face.
Doan Thi Huong and Siti
Aisyah were arrested
and now face the death penalty by hanging.
I didn't know at first.
ASRIA NUR HASAN:
I was at prayer.
Praying.
Reciting Qur'an at a funeral.
A friend had died.
And then I found out.
I felt,
how could I, as a parent...
it felt like...
how could something like this happen?
What could have brought
her to do such a thing?
I think she didn't know what she was doing.
If I asked her to do something,
she would do it.
That's the kind of person she is.
I've never actually seen
this photo.
Wow.
My obsession with North Korea
goes back a long way.
I started covering North Korea
in 2004.
And I have not stopped yet.
So, when the assassination
happened,
I came out of a yoga class, it
was like nine o'clock at night,
and I looked at my phone
and saw it had blown up.
Kim Jong-nam has been
assassinated.
Kim Jong-nam, at one point,
was the favorite son of Kim Jong-il,
the former leader of
North Korea.
He has been known as
a potential rival for Kim Jong-un.
And it's raising suspicions
that Kim Jong-un
may have once again marked one
of his own relatives for death.
It was so surprising to
me, you know, the footage,
to see Kim Jong-nam
standing in this airport.
I mean, it's so amazing
to think, you know,
I was trying to find Kim Jong-nam for
several years before he was killed,
and just to see him walking
around, no hat, no sunglasses.
It's really like, wow, I wish I
had have been able to talk to him.
And there's this myth
that the Kim family
was descended from Mount Paektu,
which is this mountain
at the top of North Korea
on the border with China,
that is the mythical home
of all Korean people.
And so the Kim regime
has used this to say,
"We were divinely ordained
to lead North Korea,"
and it's called
the Paektu bloodline.
So Kim Il-sung passed down
the leadership of North Korea
to his son, Kim Jong-il,
using this whole Paektu
bloodline mythology
as the basis for his legitimacy.
So when it came time
for Kim Jong-il
to anoint one of his sons,
it should have gone
to Kim Jong-nam.
Are you Kim Jong-nam?
- Are you Kim Jong-nam?
- No.
I cannot tell you.
It's my privacy, man.
Kim Jong-nam was the
first-born son of Kim Jong-il.
And, in fact,
Kim Jong-nam's mother
was a famous actress
who Kim Jong-il spotted
and took her basically
as his wife.
But Kim Jong-il really doted
on Kim Jong-nam.
He was absolutely besotted
with this boy
and really seemed to relish his
time as a father at the beginning.
Kim Jong-nam and Kim Jong-un
grew up entirely separate.
They had different mothers.
And there's a 10-year
age difference.
Kim Jong-un's mother was another
woman, she was a famous dancer,
and was very ambitious
and very present.
She was advocating and agitating
for her son, for him to be
the leader of North Korea,
and she had a very powerful
influence in the system there.
So, at the beginning
of the 2000s,
Kim Jong-nam was caught in this
very embarrassing situation.
He had taken
his young family to Tokyo
and was busted
by the Japanese police.
He'd gone in under a fake
Dominican Republic passport,
using a Chinese name, Pang
Xiong, which means "fat bear."
And he said, you know, he just
wanted to take his kid to Disneyland.
It was extremely embarrassing
for the regime.
America is North Korea's
number-one enemy
and Disneyland, you know,
can you get more American than Disneyland?
But, in fact, there were rumors
that Kim Jong-un's mother actually
tipped off the Japanese police
to the arrival of Kim Jong-nam
in Japan
because she wanted to make sure
that he could not become the
next leader of North Korea.
So, Kim Jong-nam struck
a deal with his father
to be allowed to leave
North Korea.
He moved to Macau,
a Chinese territory,
where he was able to live
a kind of normal life.
But he was ruled out
of the succession line.
And throughout history,
we've seen
brothers being sidelined
in this way.
From Cain and Abel to Romulus and
Remus at the foundation of Rome.
Brothers are so threatening
because they can stake a claim
to leadership
that nobody else can.
So, when I discovered that
Kim Jong-nam had been killed,
I hopped on the first flight
that I could get to Kuala Lumpur.
Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to the foreign journalists,
welcome to Malaysia as well.
We have arrested two ladies,
and we have identified both of them.
The Malaysian police announced that they have
arrested Siti Aisyah and Doan Thi Huong.
They also announced there were
eight North Korean suspects.
And out of those eight,
four of them were at the airport
on the same day as Siti Aisyah and Doan,
And they left the country immediately
after Kim Jong-nam's attack.
And then, they also announced the arrest of
one North Korean guy,
Ri Jong Choi.
who was living in Malaysia
and he happens to be a chemist.
Ri Jong Choi,
the suspect that was detained...
Can you clear up, because there are rumors that
he was the driver or he was a chemistry expert...
He is subject of our investigation.
How can we tell you?
We found out that Ri Jong Choi is
on the payroll of the North Korean embassy.
He lives in a house paid by the North
Korean government in Kuala Lumpur.
I was just wondering...
the two female suspects,
did they know the substance was toxic?
Well, I think you have
seen the video, right?
You have seen the -
the lady who was moving away
with her hands like this,
towards the bathroom. Towards the washroom.
So she knew very well that
it is toxic and she
needs to wash her hands.
Hello.
Yes, speaking.
Yes.
Because our theory is that this was
a political assassination.
More than just the two girls being involved
in an ordinary murder case.
Well, we do not know exactly what type of
evidence the police have in hand.
When we approach any case,
we will not accept what
our client tells us.
We will investigate on our own and see
whether our client is telling the truth.
After Siti Aisyah was arrested,
we saw her the very next day.
And there in prison, there were
other inmates who told her that,
"You are going to be the next 'BA.'"
"BA" is the -
banduan akhir.
That means on death row.
You are going to be the next one.
In Malaysia, if they're found guilty,
then it's a mandatory death sentence.
That is hanging by the
neck until you are dead.
They will put a sandbag,
which would be sufficient to snap
your neck immediately when...
You will die instantaneously.
Okay, all right, then.
I will check that. Thank you.
We advised her to be very careful
not to talk about her story to anyone,
even Doan.
Because we don't know Doan's story.
The girls don't know each other,
and we don't know whether Doan is
working together with the North Koreans.
Not bad, eh?
I can get the documents I want.
Very organized.
Okay, this is quite clear.
The victim is here.
And then I think the
incident takes place...
Okay, this is on the day
of the incident itself.
This is her action of putting
up the hands like that.
And that is the crucial moment.
I first met Doan in prison.
There were two officers from
the Vietnamese embassy and myself.
And when she was brought to us,
she was happy to see
officers of the embassy,
who could speak her own language.
She was hopeful then at that point of time.
These are all the certificates Doan
has earned since she was little.
She was always well-behaved,
a good student.
Nothing troublesome.
We are farmers, my parents were farmers.
Doan's mother passed away three years ago,
before all this happened.
Doan was a good girl.
She was even terrified
of butchering a chicken.
She wouldn't dare kill it.
I always had to do it for her.
She went to Hanoi for
college a few years ago.
I think the world out there seduced her.
When suddenly this happened,
everybody in the family was shocked.
I sent her a letter encouraging her
that if she did do it,
she should confess it.
Whatever she did or however it happened,
only she knows.
We love her very much,
but we don't know how to help her.
It has been seven days since the incident.
There is an allegation that the
arrested female suspects murdered him.
The Malaysian police are desperate
to shift the blame on us.
Last Friday night,
they raided the condominium
of our citizen here in Kuala Lumpur
and forcibly arrested him.
The North Korean ambassador in Malaysia
held a press conference
talking about Ri Jong Chol,
the North Korean chemist who was arrested.
This is a grave human rights violation.
Saying that they have distrust
in the Malaysian police investigation.
Malaysia reacted
by expelling the North Korean ambassador.
From there, North Korea issued a ban
on Malaysians leaving North Korea.
So all these people who are
embassy staff and their families,
they are trapped in North Korea.
So they are basically hostages.
And then, in March,
Malaysia and North Korea
actually had a negotiation.
North Korea demanded the
release of Ri Jong Choi,
as well as the release of two suspects
who were hiding in the
North Korean embassy.
They are a North Korean embassy official
and an employee of Air Koryo,
the North Korean national airline.
They also demanded the body of Kim Jong-nam
to be sent back to North Korea.
After years in exile,
the murdered half-brother
of North Korea's dictator
has finally gone home.
It's a clean sweep
tonight for Kim Jong-un.
North Korea's dangerous young
leader has gotten the body
of his murdered half-brother
Kim Jong-nam.
And Malaysia has released
three North Koreans
wanted for questioning
in the murder.
Chaos at Beijing's
airport Friday
as North Korean Ri Jong Chol
made his way through the crowd.
Ri was released and then
deported by Malaysian authorities
after being held as a suspect
in the murder of North Korean leader
Kim Jong-un's estranged half-brother.
It was very difficult to
bear but I said to myself
that I must get through this,
because I cannot let them do this
to me as a North Korean citizen,
when they dare to trample
on the honor of North Korea.
At the same time,
Malaysia got back nine of its citizens,
who had been stuck in North Korea
during this diplomatic standoff.
The Malaysians insist
that the three North Koreans
were not traded
for nine hostages.
We are finished with them,
so that's why we allowed them to go.
Malaysia is one of those weird countries who
actually has diplomatic relations with North Korea.
A good working relationship
with North Korea.
It is very, very suspicious.
Why did you allow such important
witnesses to go back to North Korea?
If you decide to save the nine Malaysian hostages
in exchange for all those that they demanded,
I feel that they don't have the right
to charge the two girls,
because you have compromised
their right of defense.
The trial begins today
for the two women accused
of murdering Kim Jong-nam,
the half-brother
of the North Korean premier.
The women claim
hey are innocent.
If found guilty, they face
Malaysia's mandatory death penalty.
PROSECUTOR: Siti Aisyah and Doan Thi Huong
PROSECUTOR: are each charged with murder
PROSECUTOR: along with four others at large
PROSECUTOR: against a man named Kim Chol.
Inside the courtroom, the prosecution is
referring to Kim Jong-nam as "Kim Chol,"
which is the take name that
appears on his passport.
And what was interesting
and perhaps controversial,
is that the prosecution also charged
four North Koreans who are still at large,
but was very reluctant to
name the four North Koreans.
HISYAM: I think we ought to know before
the trial starts who the four persons are.
HISYAM: The prosecution has
got a legal duty to disclose,
HISYAM: at the same time
a moral duty to disclose.
JUDGE: I find the
omission to state the name
JUDGE: of the four persons at large
JUDGE: does not make the charge ambiguous.
JUDGE: Objection is hereby overruled.
It was not a good start
for us.
No matter what the position
that the prosecution is taking,
you cannot ignore the political
angle of the assassination.
Kim Jong-il died in 2011.
And Kim Jong-un was officially
unveiled as the successor
when he was 25 years old.
There was a great deal of skepticism
when Kim Jong-un was announced.
He had no experience.
He was barely out of college
at that stage.
And there was the question
if the old guard in North
Korea, if they would tolerate
this young upstart coming in
and ordering them around.
So there was a lot of doubt in
Seoul, in Tokyo, in Washington,
that Kim Jong-un would be able
to keep this totalitarian
regime together.
So, since Kim Jong-un came
into power,
he has very kind of
strategically acted
to instill loyalty
at the top of the regime,
to make sure that the people
who support him,
the elites who keep him
in power,
have even more reason
than ever to keep him there.
So, the millennials of Pyongyang
can now do yoga classes
and drink cappuccinos
and they live a much better life
than under his father
or his grandfather.
But the other part is fear.
He also needs to keep them
terrified.
And the way that he has done
this is by getting rid of anybody
who threatens him,
who questions him,
who may in some way suggest
that he's not the legitimate
leader of North Korea.
And as part of that, a lot of
senior figures in the regime
have been purged.
Even his uncle,
Jang Song-thaek, was executed.
And this is very much Kim
Jong-un's MO for staying in power.
No one is safe.
And it was around that time,
you know, Kim Jong-nam
was traveling a lot around
southeast Asia,
and he made, you know,
several surprising remarks,
where he seemed to question his
brother's legitimacy to lead
and whether North Korea should
have hereditary succession.
Hello, are you Mr. Kim Jong-nam?
Yes, I am. Hello.
As the first son,
are you fine not being the successor?
Personally I'm against a third-generation
succession of the dynasty.
And because of that,
because he was, you know, threatening
Kim Jong-un's right to lead North Korea,
Kim Jong-nam was somebody who
certainly would be considered a threat
by Kim Jong-un and whose life
could be in danger.
Today the prosecution is calling Dr. Raja,
who is the government's
chemical weapons expert.
DR. RAJA: My lord, VX is the deadliest
nerve agent ever created by a human being.
DR. RAJA: A drop of VX is
sufficient to cause fatality.
DR. RAJA: We identified
VX on blazer of victim
DR. RAJA: and face and
eye mucosa of victim.
DR. RAJA: We found
degradation product of VX
DR. RAJA: on sleeveless
shirt of Siti Aisyah.
DR. RAJA: We found VX
on LOL t-shirt of Doan.
PROSECUTOR: What if just one drop of
VX came into contact to human skin?
DR. RAJA: If you decontaminate
within fifteen minutes,
DR. RAJA: you most likely will not
see any effect or some delayed effect.
So the big takeaway from his
testimony is that it answers
this lingering question of why the VX
chemical, which we know is very toxic,
can kill Kim Jong-nam but it did
not kill Siti Aisyah and Doan.
He explained that because the palm,
number one, is thick,
the skin is thick.
Number two, it has a lot of fats.
So it was very difficult for the VX liquid
to penetrate through the
skin into the bloodstream.
Unlike when VX is applied onto the eyes.
The Organization for the
Prohibition of Chemical Weapons,
which represents 192 nations,
issued a statement saying,
"Any use of chemical weapons
is deeply disturbing."
While North Korea has not
acknowledged it has chemical weapons,
South Korea estimates the
regime has a stockpile
of up to 5,000 metric tons.
Now, if somebody brings a
chemical weapon into your country,
to me that tantamounts
to a declaration of war.
And VX,
who can have possession of VX?
No ordinary people.
GOOI: I refer to the things that were
GOOI: seized or obtained from the
North Korean scientist by the name of
GOOI: Ri Jong Chol.
GOOI: Were you taken to his house?
DR. RAJA: No, my lord.
GOOI: You therefore have
no knowledge whether
GOOI: his house was in
fact a clandestine lab?
DR. RAJA: No, my lord.
The investigation is very
shallow, I would say.
Ri Jong Choi is a chemist.
The police did not even investigate
whether the VX actually came from him.
Both the girls,
they never washed their clothes.
They never disposed of their clothes.
If they knew VX was so poisonous,
if they actually knew it was VX,
would they take the chance
of exposing themselves
to such a dangerous poison?
Okay.
When Siti was arrested,
we went to visit her in prison.
My first impression of, uh...
her whole demeanor,
whole conduct.
She doesn't know anything.
That is when we found out
Siti's story.
SITI:
When I was arrested,
I was with my roommate in my room.
SITI:
My room was not locked. It never was.
Then the police pushed the door open.
SITI: The police asked,
"Where were you on the 13th?"
SITI:
"At the airport," I said.
"With whom?"
SITI:
"With Mr. Chang, my boss," I said.
"Can you call him?"
SITI: So I called Mr. Chang,
but the number wasn't active.
SITI: The police asked, "Who are you?
Are you a spy?"
SITI:
"What did you do that caused
that man in the airport to die?"
SITI: I was confused.
I didn't understand what they meant.
SITI:
"You are involved in the premeditated
murder of the Korean president's brother."
SITI:
I was shocked. "You're kidding."
"I was doing a video shoot."
SITI:
"Is this part of the video prank?"
Siti,
she in fact thought that she was
part of a prank show.
And we had to persuade her,
to tell her, "Look,
someone really died.
This is not a prank show.
And now you are being charged for murder."
As criminal lawyers,
we have our reservations.
We have to be very objective.
Okay, not to believe 100%.
The issue is whether they
know what they were doing.
And could they have been duped to believe
that they are acting in a prank show?
HISYAM TEH POH TEIK:
When Doan grew up,
she went to Hanoi to get her education.
Although she studied accountancy
in a private university,
after that she couldn't
get a job as an accountant.
She ended up working
as a waitress in a pub.
And during this time,
she was doing modeling.
And she even took part in Vietnam Idol.
Okay.
Her aspiration is to be an actress.
She wants to be famous.
Even in her statement to the police,
she described her occupation as an actress.
Do you need an interpreter to
translate from English to Vietnamese?
DOAN: No, because I can try
speak and understand English.
DOAN:
I work as waitress for three years.
I have a colleague named Thuy.
DOAN:
In early December 2016,
she called my cellphone.
DOAN:
She said,
"Do you want working for company
about short movie or funny video?
DOAN:
Come to shop Hay Bar.
We are waiting here."
DOAN:
I come alone and
DOAN: I saw Thuy and a guy
sitting near the counter bar.
DOAN:
I asked him, "What's your name?"
And he answered me in Vietnamese language.
DOAN:
"Call me Mr. Y."
He explained about the funny video.
DOAN:
He asked me how much I want for a month.
DOAN: I feel shy but I say,
"I want US dollar 1000."
DOAN: He tell me his boss
can pay for the funny video.
So now we are finding out
that both women are claiming
that they have been going
around Asia for months
doing prank shows for
what they believe to be
a Japanese production company.
And their last prank
would be the murder
assassination of Kim Jong-nam.
There's this culture of
doing amateur prank videos.
I think it came from people
watching shows like "Jackass." '
And with the access allowed by social media
nowadays, people want to do that themselves.
So it's not really out of the ordinary for
people to do prank videos here in Asia.
And Doan was doing this
series of prank shows.
In 2016, Doan took part in two pranks
which were uploaded onto YouTube.
This is Doan now.
I want to emphasize that this prank
is not connected whatsoever
to the North Koreans.
And this is one year before the
incident with Kim Jong-nam.
I slap you, yeah?
Is it funny?
It's not uhh...
Yes, it is.
But whether it's funny does not matter.
This is part of the evidence
to show that in fact she was
acting in funny video clips
a long time before she
met the North Koreans.
Siti is here.
The one wearing sunglasses.
I really want her to come home.
Siti went to school until 6th grade.
And then, in time, she needed to find work.
SITI:
When I was young,
I saw my family was poor.
SITI:
I wanted to help my family.
So I went to Jakarta.
SITI:
I found work at a clothing factory.
SITI: And that is when I
got married to the owner.
SITI:
And then, I had my son when I was 17.
I liked being a mother,
SITI:
but I was young and had to work a lot.
At the clothing factory,
SITI:
people saw me as being that
little girl from the village.
SITI: I would work from
7:30 or 8 AM until midnight.
SITI:
I didn't have any other work
experience so I had no other choice.
SITI:
Then in 2012,
my husband and I got a divorce.
SITI: And my son went to live
with my ex-husband's father.
SITI:
Of course I was sad.
SITI: But my life was just to
work and find money to eat.
I think for Siti...
life was difficult.
She had to survive.
And so in the hope
of a better life,
for her and her family,
she came to Kuala Lumpur
to look for a better job.
SITI:
Kuala Lumpur, in my opinion,
is progressive compared to Jakarta.
SITI:
In Kuala Lumpur I could go out around town.
SITI: I saw lots of
fashionable people at the mall.
SITI:
From there I learned,
oh, I can change and be pretty.
SITI:
In the beginning, I was happy.
For a young migrant,
women especially,
coming to Malaysia,
it can be a very dangerous world.
Most often they come here
believing in a promise of a secure job,
but when they arrive,
they find themselves in a
very different environment,
the underbelly of Kuala Lumpur.
And some of them being
forced into prostitution,
sexual slavery.
And they usually don't
have any say about it.
When I first met Siti,
she was a village girl,
still a teenager.
She had a job working at a spa.
I knew that she did not like
her job as a sex worker.
But she had no other choice.
This was the only kind of
work to earn good money.
According to Siti,
there was this person
John, this taxi driver,
who introduced her
to the North Koreans.
There were, what-- two, three
attempts for us to meet John.
But the police,
they could not produce him.
They said he was uncontactable.
I will start from the beginning, okay?
One night, this guy approached me
in front of the mall entrance.
He said he wanted to go to
Kuala Lumpur City Centre.
He said his name was James,
and he was from Japan.
He was looking for girls
to act in a prank video.
He told me, "If you find any
girls, then give me a call."
Around 3 o'clock in the
morning, the club closes.
The girls there will come outside
and look for customers.
That night, I saw Siti there by herself.
SITI: John asked,
"Do you want to do a video shoot?
SITI:
A guy from Japan
SITI: is looking for an
actress for a video shoot."
I had asked many girls there
if they'd be interested,
but Siti was the only person who agreed.
The entire text messages, we went through.
Hundreds of pages.
Thousands.
Thousands of pages.
Nothing to indicate that
she had anything sinister or that she
was involved in the assassination.
SITI:
After getting to Pavilion,
SITI: John introduced me to
the boss from Japan, James.
SITI:
James put baby lotion on my hands.
I was instructed to hold someone's hand,
SITI:
look at their face, then say sorry.
SITI: I didn't think the
prank videos were that funny.
SITI: But he convinced me
that every Japanese prank show
SITI:
has its own style.
Then he paid me 400 ringgits (96 USD),
SITI:
I thought, "That's easy money
for doing such a simple thing."
SITI:
And I could send it home to my parents.
1-6-8, there.
This is a photo of James.
This is John, the taxi driver
who introduced her to James.
And this is Siti, at the very
first meeting at Pavilion.
This photo--
Someone who knew John
saw him there
and took a photograph
and posted it in a group chat.
It is coincidental.
Thank God for this photo.
The photograph essentially
confirms Siti'’s story.
Today the prosecution is putting the
investigating officer to the witness stand,
Wan Azirul.
He is the prosecution's
star witness in this case.
PROSECUTOR: You mentioned earlier about the role of
the four North Koreans. Can you tell us their role?
WAN AZIRUL: The four suspects were the people who provided
both Siti and Doan with ongoing training exercises
WAN AZIRUL: to ensure that their actions on
the day of the incident would be successful.
HISYAM: Objection, my lord.
The investigating officer
used the word "training."
- Yes. That's right.
- We objected.
This is pure interpretation
by the investigating officer.
His version is Doan and Siti Aisyah
were taking part in training.
And we have in fact strong evidence
to show that she is in fact
being tricked,
being duped to do what she did.
DOAN:
Mr. Y said meet at big theater Hanoi.
He told me how to do action in the video.
DOAN:
He said go talk and give surprise kiss
on the cheek to anybody he choose.
DOAN: After that,
a Korean man - really old - came to us and
DOAN:
we went to coffee shop nearby and sitting.
Mr. Y said, "This is my boss."
DOAN:
I asked the bass his name.
Mr. Y told me, "Hanamori means uncle."
DOAN:
"So, just sail him Hanamori."
Siti, there was a prank
on the 9th of January.
At Mandarin Oriental.
And she made a video of James.
James could not speak proper English.
Listen, listen.
Turn off the camera.
Turn off!
And they were communicating
using Google Translate.
So to ensure that the
whole thing will go well,
they introduce Mr. Chang.
SITI: Mr. Chang was very
good at speaking Indonesian.
SITI:
He was different from James.
Chang was a little... flirtatious.
The prank jobs that they
were doing at that time,
we call them "mistaken identity."
They come from behind,
close somebody's eyes.
Like, "Guess who I am?" sort of thing.
She was paid a few hundred US dollars.
And I think that was a fairly
good remuneration for her.
Why you filming me?
SITI:
They told me,
"You'll go to Singapore,
to America... everywhere.
SITI: You'll become famous
as the video prank actress."
Doan did a prank at the Vietnamese airport.
And, in fact, we have the DVD.
That is Doan here in white.
DOAN:
Mr. Y gave my hand Johnson baby cream.
He said I make surprise same like before.
Okay, watch this gentleman closely.
And on the other side,
there you see?
Doan running,
coming behind the gentleman.
Yep.
She did the prank.
And you see a gentleman here
videoing the prank.
There you are: Mr. Y.
A few days later,
Doan took a flight.
She came to Kuala Lumpur
together with Mr. Y,
and one more prank at the KLIA airport.
Siti had three days of pranks,
all at the arrival of the Kuala
Lumpur International Airport.
And then she posted
a video of KLIA.
You know, if I was going
to assassinate someone,
surely I would not tell them
where I got trained.
As young women, they had documented
so much of this on social media.
I mean, one of the great things
about technology here
is that it did create this trail
which showed the relationships
between the women
and their North Korean handlers
that could enable them
to put up a defense.
PROSECUTOR: Based on your investigation,
do you agree that this was a prank?
WAN AZIRUL: To me, the "prank" that was
acted out by both of them
WAN AZIRUL: is something that doesn't
make any sense and is illogical.
"The specific act was more of an attack
that was specifically targeted
and perpetrated by both defendants
on the day of the incident."
As the investigating officer,
you are supposed to investigate
based on the evidence,
you are not supposed to
come out with judgement.
It shows he already made up his mind
early on that these girls are guilty,
and he and the prosecution are basically
reading from the same book.
Look at the evidence
completely and entirely.
These girls have got no motive whatsoever.
But look at the North Koreans.
North Korea has got an interest.
Kim Jong-nam had been living
in Macau for more than a decade.
And there are a number of rumors
that this was not
the first attempt on his life,
that Kim Jong-un had tried repeatedly
to assassinate Kim Jong-nam.
In fact, the South Korean
intelligence reported
that Kim Jong-nam had actually written a
letter to his brother, saying, you know,
"Please stop trying to kill me,"
like, "I am not a threat
to you."
You know, "I do not want
to be the leader.
"Please let me and my family...
please let us live our lives."
So he was extremely careful and
conscious that he was always in danger.
But because he was living
in China,
for North Korea to assassinate
Kim Jong-nam,
it's very difficult because, you
know, North Korea is reliant on China.
They are North Korea's number-one
benefactor, patron state.
And from China's point of view,
they had given Kim Jong-nam
kind of exile protection,
and in some ways were maybe
keeping him in reserve,
that if they wanted to replace
Kim Jong-un,
they could install Kim Jong-nam
as the leader of North Korea.
So there's no way
that North Korea could ever
conduct such an audacious
assassination,
or any assassination,
on Chinese soil.
So they had to make sure
they caught Kim Jong-nam
when he was outside of China.
On February 8th, 2017,
just like days before he was -
before he was killed,
Kim Jong-nam flew to Langkawi,
which is a resort island in
the north part of Malaysia.
He checked in at the Westin Hotel.
So, here we have Kim Jong-nam
in the elevator
at the Westin Hotel in Langkawi,
with this man, who was later
reported to be a CIA agent.
It's never been confirmed
that this man was, in fact,
working for the CIA.
But during the course of my reporting,
I discovered that Kim Jong-nam
had become a CIA informant
after his brother took power.
So he met with this CIA agent,
and they spent two hours together.
And he flew back to Kuala Lumpur,
where he was killed.
After the murder,
Malaysian police went through
Kim Jong-nam's laptop.
And they were able to identity that
data was removed from the
laptop into a USB drive
on the day where Kim Jong-nam
met with the American agent.
In his bag, they found 138,000 US dollars,
which seems to suggest that the money was
payment for the data that was transferred.
The CIA likes to say that North Korea
is the blackest of all the black holes.
They have so little information about
what's happening inside North Korea.
And Kim Jong-nam,
the one thing that he had
that very few other people had
was information about the
inner workings of this regime.
And if North Korea had
discovered that Kim Jong-nam
was providing information to the
American intelligence service,
this alone would be reason
for the North Koreans
to try to eliminate him.
DOAN:
On February 4th, 2017,
DOAN: me and Mr. Y together
go to Kuala Lumpur again.
This video clip shows Doan
checking into the hotel.
She had this teddy bear with her.
Huge one.
About the same size as her.
And Mr. Y instructed her
to practice the prank on the teddy bear.
When we started this case,
some of the CCTV footage
was leaked to a Japanese TV station.
And that went viral.
Whereas, the defense counsel,
we have put in lots of
letters to the police
asking for the CCTV footage,
with no reply whatsoever.
Now, we finally received the CCTV footage
some six months after the incident.
This is in KLIA2 airport departure hall.
Mr. O Jong-gil
in the white cap
and Hanamori, the guy in the purple shirt.
Hanamori is the mastermind
of the operation, but
O Jong-gil, he is also closely involved.
We like to call him the
Godfather of the operation.
DOAN:
Mr. Y said video on the
13th is very important.
DOAN:
So I wear long sleeve
white shirt with LOL print
DOAN:
and I make hairstyle like wave
and makeup beautifully.
DOAN: Mr. Y said company
rent new actor and actress
DOAN: to make more effective
video and put on YouTube.
Siti Aisyah just arrived and
she is taking a seat across from Mr. Chang.
On the table we can actually see
a smartphone mounted on a selfie stick.
SITI: He said,
"Today there will be hidden cameras,
SITI:
so not just me."
So here you can see Siti
high five Mr. Chang.
Either she is oblivious
about what she's about to do,
or she is
so well trained
that the act of killing someone
is just another day for her.
DOAN:
Mr. Y said the new actor
is a fat man and no hair.
This is Kim Jong-nam.
He is looking at the board
to check out his flight to Macau.
If you look very closely,
this over here is Siti.
She is standing next to this column.
She is not alone over there.
She is actually with Mr. Chang,
who is hiding behind this column.
And over here,
waiting at the table is Hanamori,
the mastermind.
You can see that when Kim Jong-nam enters,
Hanamori walked toward
Mr. Chang and Siti Aisyah,
indicating that Kim Jong-nam is coming.
And as Kim Jong-nam is
walking towards the kiosk,
you can see that Siti moves
and hid behind this column.
SITI:
Suddenly, Mr. Chang said,
"That's the one, in the gray jacket."
SITI:
He gave me the baby oil.
And now we can see Mr. Chang.
He walks past Kim Jong-nam
to watch the attack happen.
DOAN:
Mr. Y gave me oil on my hand.
He told me, "Don't look."
DOAN: He said,
"Just look at the actor and actress."
I saw the new actress
put hands on his face
from the back.
DOAN:
I ran and do the same surprise.
I put my hand on his eyes.
DOAN:
I say sorry to him.
I running and go.
Looking from this angle
you can see Kim Jong-nam.
He stumbled back.
It's very possible for him to actually start to
feel the effect of the VX chemical right away.
SITI: He reacted like he was scared.
It scared me too.
SITI:
So I ran away.
WAN AZIRUL: In this image we see a woman.
WAN AZIRUL: She walks quickly and is seen
WAN AZIRUL: trying to
avoid touching her bag.
WAN AZIRUL: She holds her hands as though she
doesn't want to touch the two moving rails,
WAN AZIRUL: shaking her
hands like it's burning.
This video is important
because you can see Siti
rubbing the palm of her hand.
And Wan Azirul's testimony was that Siti
was trying to avoid contact.
If she had known it was VX,
you know, the most lethal poison,
she would surely not have
rubbed the palm of her hands.
WAN AZIRUL: The CCTV
recording clearly shows Doan
WAN AZIRUL: and her hands
seemed very uncomfortable.
DOAN:
I felt my hand oily and smelly
DOAN: and I don't want it to
dirty my LOL white T-shirt.
As Kim Jong-nam was dying,
these North Koreans,
they were subsequently seen in the CCTV
going towards the toilet
and change their clothes.
Then they were immediately met by the
secretary of the North Korean embassy
and the staff in the Air Koryo,
who facilitated their easy
passage through the immigration.
If you look here at this moment,
you can see them laughing.
This is like within two hours
after they killed Kim Jong-nam.
And then they flew immediately to Jakarta,
the first flight they could
take to connect them to Dubai
and to Vladivostok and back to
Pyongyang, North Korea.
The four North Koreans have escaped.
Ri Jong Choi,
the staff of the North Korean Embassy,
and the staff in the Air Koryo,
all were allowed to go back to North Korea.
And James,
nobody knows where is James today.
All the North Koreans were untouched.
But somebody has got to be charged,
because somebody is dead.
So the two girls,
they become scapegoats of the prosecution.
WAN SHAHARUDDIN WAN LADIN:
We have presented our case,
so now it is for them to
explain their conduct.
The two lawyers mentioned that this
whole plot is a political conspiracy,
that North Korea wants to murder...
it's not these two women.
I don't care.
There is no evidence of political plot.
The four North Koreans who ran away
didn't apply the VX to the victim.
It's not important for us to prove.
For me, sitting through the
prosecution's stage of the trial,
it is pretty clear that
the prosecution, and by
extension, the government,
want to convict these two women.
In the international stage it would
look very bad for Malaysia to have
somebody of a high profile as
Kim Jong-nam to be
murdered in broad daylight
at its biggest international airport.
It's a big shame for the country.
So in a typical mentality of saving face,
someone has to take the blame,
to take the fall for it.
Just from a judicial point of view,
yes, these women were caught on camera
carrying out this act.
They were very clearly the ones
who had assassinated, technically,
Kim Jong-nam.
So Malaysia did need to act,
did need to hold somebody to account,
and the fact is that the masterminds
of it were back in North Korea.
So now the assassination
of Kim Jong-nam
has been really fundamental
to phase one
of Kim Jong-un's leadership
and to the way that he has
been able to stay in power.
And once he had taken out
all his rivals,
he had proven his strength
domestically...
He was ready for phase two.
North Korea best not make any
more threats to the United States.
They will be met
with fire and fury
like the world has never seen.
He wanted to get
the world's attention.
I think now that he has proven he had
a credible nuclear weapons program,
he is now starting this process
of trying to look like a
respectable international statesman
and seems very strong
and very confident
and very much in control
of this regime.
Hello.
Okay, good.
Who is this, please?
Ah, okay, all right,
all right, fine.
Now that the prosecution
has closed its case,
how do you save your client
from execution at this point?
Look at the conduct.
Two days after the incident,
Doan went back to the airport
again to the scene of crime.
Now the question is:
assuming Doan is the assassin,
assuming she is the killer,
would she go back to the
airport two days later
and be identified?
It doesn't makes sense, does it?
This is Doan.
She's coming back to the arrival hall.
You can see, she never cut her hair.
She was wearing the same shoes.
She don't know
that someone called Kim Jong-nam has died,
and police are looking for her.
DOAN: Mr. Y said today
make another video at KLIA.
DOAN:
So I go there at 8 AM
and call and text him many times.
DOAN:
But he switch off his phone.
Then, no choice,
she wanted to go back to the hotel.
She called for a taxi.
The guards came.
And she was arrested by the authorities.
The prosecution's case was
closed on the 5th of April.
And meanwhile, the girls are incarcerated.
They have already been in
the jail for one and a half years.
And that damage is irreparable.
In our criminal system here,
once the prosecution presents its case,
the judge will have to
make a decision whether
a case has been proven
against both of the girls.
The judge could either acquit the girls
or call for their defense.
JUDGE: My reading of my finding
will take quite some time.
JUDGE: So please bear with me.
JUDGE: There is bound to be unhappiness.
It took two and a half hours
for the judgement to be delivered.
It was an eighty-two page judgement.
JUDGE: The CCTV footage shows both women
holding their hands away from themselves.
JUDGE: To me, the precise timing and
the use of the VX as a chemical weapon
JUDGE: all goes to support that they knew that the
liquid placed on their hands were toxic substances.
I think that was the moment where I...
on the margins of my notes I wrote that
they are fucked.
And I think these girls are going to hang.
JUDGE: The sole purpose of prank is fun.
JUDGE: It is evident that none
of the features of "prank"
JUDGE: can be seen or found
to exist in the CCTV footage.
JUDGE: I find that the contention
that they were merely duped
JUDGE: into carrying out the act
could not possibly hold water.
JUDGE: I am of the firm view
that the accused persons
JUDGE: were the perpetrators
leading to the death of Kim Chol,
JUDGE: and I must therefore call upon them
JUDGE: to enter their defense
on their respective charges.
How is your client feeling?
She is obviously disappointed with
the ruling made by his Lordship.
Will you still try your defense
of the prank, given that--
Oh, yes. That has been our
defense consistently
from day one until now.
And we will pursue it until
the end of the defense's case.
But the judge said it's not a prank
because nobody laughed?
That is his finding at this point of time.
He has not heard Doan.
At this point of time,
Siti and Doan have been
in jail almost two years.
I think the girls, um,
really have no one apart from each other.
Because they are kept separately
from all other inmates.
Even then they are separated
from one another.
SITI: With Doan,
when we first entered the prison,
SITI:
she was asked by the Malaysian police
which part of Vietnam she was from,
SITI:
and she said, "Hanoi."
I didn't know her name,
SITI:
so I called her "Noi" from Hanoi.
DOAN:
We have separate cells
so we cannot see each other.
DOAN:
We must talk louder to hear.
SITI: Sometimes when I was about to
eat, I would say,
SITI:
"Hanoi, let's eat."
And she would say the same thing,
SITI:
"Okay, let's eat, Aisyah."
After about a year in prison,
SITI:
I started to joke around more with Noi,
and chit-chat.
SITI: That was when we
started to be close friends.
DOAN:
Siti is very funny.
Also very...
DOAN:
good heart.
Only...
DOAN:
me understand her and
her understand me.
DOAN:
We become
like sisters, become best friends.
DOAN:
When we together,
I can feel her heart.
DOAN:
That's why she can believe me
and I can believe her.
In preparation for the defense of Doan,
we spent about total
fourteen hours with her.
To go through her statement,
discuss the evidence with her.
PRAYER ROOM
Doan is a bit anxious, obviously.
A bit tense,
because today she is taking the stand for
the first time in her entire life.
She is aware that her case will be watched
by people throughout the world.
There will definitely be pressure on her.
But I think she...
she's prepared.
On Saturday, before the trial started,
my friend texted Gooi.
And Gooi sent this
rather vague
text back to her
saying, "Bring all your
team down on Monday.
There is going to be big news."
Azura.
So I met with Selvi,
throwing some guesses at her.
You guys found one of the North Koreans?
You guys are going to bring James here?
And she was like,
"I don't know. You just wait.
You just wait."
The lead prosecutor Mohammad Iskandar Ahmad
got up, looked at the judge, and he said,
PROSECUTOR: There's something that I
would like to address today, my Lord.
PROSECUTOR: I am requesting...
PROSECUTOR: Your honor, I...
PROSECUTOR: I request to withdraw
PROSECUTOR: the charge against Siti Aisyah.
I literally was like,
"What?!"
The judge clearly looked surprised
that this happened,
but then he said,
JUDGE: The court has
determined that Siti Aisyah,
JUDGE: the first defendant,
is hereby released.
JUDGE: All right?
JUDGE: You can go.
I think Siti was trying to
process what was going on.
So she got up and grabbed
Doan and hugged her.
And then she left the courtroom.
How are you feeling?
I feel...
I feel like I'm...
Did they tell you before?
- No, I didn't know.
- You just found out now?
Uh-huh.
I feel...
pretty surprised.
Who was that? Aisyah?!
Oh my God!
What the hell just happened?
Yeah, she was released without...
Today, the
prosecution informed the court that
they declined to further prosecute
the case against Siti Aisyah.
So Siti Aisyah has been
discharged from the court today.
The decision is...
The decision is the decision of the
attorney general, the public prosecutor to
decline to further prosecute.
No reasons were given.
What will happen next?
Next is that
she is a free person and
she will be going back to Jakarta.
What's going to happen to Doan?
Doan's case?
I believe since they did not indicate
anything, the case must continue.
HISYAM: My lord, the accused person
will give evidence under oath.
HISYAM: We have prepared
a written statement.
DOAN: I, Doan Thi Huong, solemnly swear
DOAN: and promise the court...
Doan was pretty traumatized
with the whole experience.
She just saw
the girl who was with her the whole time
being let go.
And she just broke down and cried.
HISYAM: We'd like to make
a representation, my lord.
Her lawyers asked the Judge
for court to be adjourned.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the charge against Siti
Aisyah was withdrawn,
whereas, as far as Doan is concerned,
the charge still remains the same.
Doan is obviously traumatized
that there's no fairness shown to her.
She's entitled to the same
kind of considerations
that the public prosecutor decides to
withdraw the charge against Siti Aisyah.
Bearing in mind the
court has found as a fact
there's a case against
both of them to answer.
To me, it's a mixed feeling.
We are happy for Siti Aisyah and yet we are
sad for Doan.
The girls drew strength from one another.
To me it would be very hard for Doan
to go through the trial
alone.
- Come, come.
- Azura, come.
One for my team.
In my heart I know Doan's innocent as well.
I've been a criminal lawyer
for the last 40 years.
Until today, I...
if you ask me what justice is, I still...
I find it very difficult
to answer that question.
At first, it does appear to be coming out
of nowhere because nobody was expecting it.
But later on we found out that
Siti's discharge is
based on the fact that the Indonesian
government has been
putting constant pressure against
the Malaysian government.
There have been backchannel
discussions at a very high level
for the release of Siti Aisyah.
President Joko Widodo discussed
the issue of Siti Aisyah
with the Malaysian Prime Minister
at Bogor Palace in June 2018.
It makes sense what Indonesia is doing
to save their citizen Siti Aisyah.
But the same cannot be said
for the Vietnamese government,
who is not doing as much to defend Doan.
Vietnam and North Korea continue
to have very close relations.
They're both communist
countries.
And there's a lot of North
Korean activity inside Vietnam.
So I think Vietnam's incentive
to speak out
and to risk angering North Korea
for the sake of this one woman,
I think, was very different from
the situation that Indonesia faced,
whereas Indonesia doesn't have those
same strong relations with North Korea.
If previously the thought of
both of them going
to be hanged
for this murder
felt really unfair,
I feel it would be even worse
if Doan were going to be hanged,
- Bye!
while Siti Aisyah goes back home.
We're just so happy.
Just so glad.
Praise be to Allah.
Certainly, I am so happy to be home,
and be with my family and friends.
But I am definitely still sad.
It's as if
those North Koreans saw me
as if my life has no value whatsoever.
Like I am a nobody, a nothing.
Doan and I grew very close
over the course of the trial.
I always gave my support to her,
and she always gave her support to me.
When I cried...
when I cried,
she would always console me.
And when she cried,
I would do the same for her.
I think of her as my own sister.
I pray she will not get the death penalty.
Doan has been very depressed. Confused.
We saw her at the prison
about two or three times.
And two or three times she told
me that she would not testify.
You see, the court has made a ruling.
The judge has called for the defense.
And the law says, if, after such ruling,
Doan decides not to testify,
she will be convicted
and sentenced to death:
There's no other option whatsoever.
So, upon arriving here this morning,
one thing I noticed is
the presence of Vietnamese
officials from the embassy,
including the Vietnamese
Ambassador to Malaysia.
Which, in a way, is
a ray of hope, I suppose for Doan.
But, at the same time,
it is still
pretty much not clear what
is going to happen to her.
The charges against her still stand
and her defense lawyers have tried to get
the Attorney General to change his mind.
So, today we will find out whether
that would happen or not.
QUIET PLEASE.
COURT IS IN SESSION.
How do you feel, Doan?
Thank you so much.
- You're happy?
- I'm happy.
Doan!
We feel very lucky and happy.
The family is very,
very lucky today and very happy.
Thank you very much.
So instead of facing a murder charge,
she is being offered to
plead guilty to a charge of causing harm,
which is a much lesser offense than murder.
Would you say it is finally
a happy ending for everyone?
We are happy this morning that
it's come to a happy ending,
that Doan can look forward - there's a
date for her that she can go back home.
And that day is very near.
One minute, one minute.
Take their photo.
One, two...
- Okay. Nice. Very good.
- Thank you.
Take off the specs.
What did you think about the most
while you were in custody?
I thought about my parents,
I thought about my country and
how much I wanted to come home.
What do you want to do
now that you're back?
I don't know what to do yet,
but I think I'd like to perform.
Like an actress. That's what I want.
Thank you.
Thank you, see you later.
Thank you, I'm very happy now.
Thank you so much.
Yeah. Yes.
It is in a way a bittersweet ending.
Seeing now that the two women are home.
Both families have their
daughters back safely.
But I don't think their
lives will ever be the same.
I only learned about Kim
Jong-nam and Kim Jong-un
after coming back to Indonesia.
I searched and read about
my case from the start,
how everything happened,
and saw photos of Kim Jong-nam.
"Oh, this is Kim Jong-nam, Kim Jong-un."
It's only now...
only now that I really understand.
I never imagined
that I could be involved in his murder.
I feel really sorry for him.
Really sorry.
- Hello, Noi?
- Oh yeah, yes?
What are you doing?
Okay. I want to -
I want to see you. I miss you.
I miss you too.
When I came back, a lot of difficult,
a lot of media and
talking. People talking.
People don't know me and Siti.
People...
just watching on the television.
People don't know
how difficult time we have had.
Before, I think
the world is pink color.
The pink world is very
beautiful and colorful. Right?
And all people is good people.
But now I can see more clear.
I can see the real world is not pink.
I will be careful in my life
to trust people.
It's the end of
the journey for these two women.
But is what happened
over the last two years,
can we say this is justice?
And is there ever going to be justice for
the late Kim Jong-nam?
For all the international
condemnation and shock
that followed this
assassination,
you know, North Korea has got away
relatively scot-free from this.
In many ways,
this is the perfect crime.
The fact that Kim Jong-un was prepared
to purge and execute his brother,
in this most spectacular fashion,
sent a message to the world that
his brutality knows no limits,
that nobody is safe.
The North Koreans never suffered
any punishment for this.
North Korea still has
an embassy in Malaysia.
You know, the relations between
them have not really suffered
as a result of this.
And Kim Jong-un,
he has been able
to come to the outside world.
And he gets his red carpet welcome
on the dais with the flags.
He gets the photo opportunity
to show himself
as an international statesman.
And now, all of a sudden,
he gets to present himself
as a peer of the most powerful
man in the world.
I just received a
beautiful letter from Kim Jong-un.
I can't show you the letter,
obviously, but it was a very personal,
very warm, very nice letter.
I saw the information about the CIA
with respect to his half-brother.
And I would tell him that would not
happen under my... under my auspices.
So this is the way that Kim
Jong-un has defied all the skepticism
and shown that he is, you know,
surprisingly adept
at being a totalitarian leader.
And I think these two women
were very unwitting pawns
in this bigger chess game.
I'm sorry about everything.
I hope
people in the world will think
me and Siti like
your friends, like
your daughters, like
your sisters.
When I was in Kajang Prison,
I'd be lying down falling asleep,
and I would stare out the window.
It was way high up on the wall.
I would pray as I gazed at the sky,
"Oh Allah, will I ever see the sky again,
in all its vastness?"